「ちはる」という歌を作りました    聴いてください
I wrote a song called "Chiharu." Please listen to it.
我写了一首叫做《千春》的歌　请听
中文翻译：肥羊菌_
翻译自英语
君の髪に冬の残り香があった
The scent of winter lingers in your hair
冬日的气息残留于你的发间
ほろ苦くて、煙みたいなアイスブルーで
It's bittersweet and a smokey ice blue
味道有些许苦涩，连同烟雾般的冰蓝色
僕の髪に春の花びらがついて
When spring flower petals caught in my hair
初春的花瓣坠在我的发梢
笑い合っていたこと
We laughed together
我们一同欢笑
もう随分前のことのように思える
Seems like such a long time ago
仿佛已是许久前的事
あまりに脆くて
Such fragility
如此脆弱
ただ散りゆく季節の幼い恋を
Young love in the twilight season
零散季节中的稚嫩感情
胸に抱いて雨を待つ
Holding it close to my heart, I wait for rain
将它关在心间　等待雨的到来
花冷えの日、またひとつ春めいていくから
A cold day during the cherry blossoms brings us closer to spring
花朵盛开期间的寒冷，又将迎来一个春天
さらさらと頬を撫でる
When my cheeks are softly caressed
当面颊被轻轻地爱抚
春の雨にまた君を思い出す
By a spring rain, I'm reminded of you
在这场春雨中　再次回想起了你
薄桃色に霞んでいく光の束をつかんだら
When I grasp a bundle of light, turning into a mist of pale pink
在抓住那束淡粉色的霞光之后
花便りがもう聞こえる
I can hear the tidings of flowers
便能听闻花的音讯
昼下がりの街はグレイスケールの海
The city in the early afternoon is a greyscale ocean
午后的街道犹如灰白色的海洋
こぬか雨だ
A light rain
一场细雨到来
傘をさしたって仕方ないね
Umbrellas make no sense
雨伞变得毫无意义
笑う君の長いまつ毛を滑った
Hoping to turn into droplets that
希望我能成为在你欢笑时
しずくになれたら
Slipped off your long lashes as you laughed
从你那长长的睫毛上滑落下来的雨滴
そんな空想さえ懐かしく思える
Now I look back fondly on such fantasies
我竟然怀念着那种空想
僕らの時間は
Our time with each other
我们彼此间的时光
ただ散りゆく季節と共に過ぎていった
Passed by together with the dispersing seasons
与消散的季节一同流逝
気づけば君の背中は春霞の向こう側
By the time I noticed, you'd already turned back and was way beyond the spring mist
当我回过神来　你已回首　朝着春霞
逃げ去ってしまった
You'd run away
逃奔走了
さらさらと頬を撫でる
When my cheeks are softly caressed
当面颊被轻轻地爱抚
春の雨にまた君を思い出す
By a spring rain, I'm reminded of you
在这场春雨中　我再次回想起了你
アスファルトに滲んでいく
Blurring into the asphalt
模糊在沥青中
花びらひとつ拾う度
Every time I pick up a flower petal
每当拾起一片花瓣
何度も踏みつけられて汚れてもなお鮮やかな桃色が
A bright pink that remains unsoiled no matter how many times it's been trampled
无论被践踏多少次也不会被污染的淡粉色
あの日から色のない霧に囚われた
Has since that day been taken prisoner by a colorless haze
自那天起　我就陷入在了无色烟雾中
僕の目には眩し過ぎたよ
Too bright for my eyes
在我的眼中过于耀眼
季節が千巡っても、またここに戻ってこようと思う
When the seasons pass a thousand times, I think I'll return to this place again
即使季节流逝千次，我也想再次回到这里
花冷えの日
On a cold day during the cherry blossoms
在花朵盛开的寒冷日子
さらさらと頬に伝う
Running down my cheeks
顺着我的脸颊流下
しずくはもう溢れてしまって
Are droplets that have overflowed
雨滴已经满溢出来了
景色全部が滲んでいく
All of the scenery before me blurs
面前的所有景色都模糊不清
君の背中が見えた気がした
I thought I saw your back
我感觉见到了你的背影
さらさらと頬を撫でる
When my cheeks are softly caressed
当面颊被轻轻地爱抚
春の雨にまた君を思い出す
By a spring rain, I'm reminded of you again
在这场春雨中　再次回想起了你
薄桃色に霞んでいく光の束をつかんだら
When I grasp a bundle of light, turning into a mist of pale pink
在抓住那束淡粉色的霞光之后
花便りがもう聞こえる
I can hear the tidings of flowers
便能听闻花的音讯
ぬるい風に冬の残り香があった
The scent of winter lingered in a lukewarm wind
冬日的气息在微温的风中徘徊
何度だって
Again and again
反反复复
君のいない春を歩いていくよ
I'll walk through spring without you
即使没有你　我也会走过春天
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
非常感谢